Guide to the Miriam Schlein Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Material, 1949-2003; Series II; 7.5
  - "I Want To Catch A Panda" (Box 28, Folder 731)
  - "Ideas" (Box 28, Folder 732-739)
  - Indian notes and clippings (Box 28, Folder 740)
  - "Is This Your Relative Proposal?" (Box 28, Folder 741)
  - Japanese folk tales (Box 28, Folder 742)
  - Jewish Holiday notes, circa 1980-1982 (Box 28, Folder 743-744)
  - "Juju-Sheep And The Python's Moonstone" (Box 29, Folder 745)
  - Kangaroo research (Box 29, Folder 746)
  - "Lady And The Panda" (Box 29, Folder 747)
  - "The Last Elephant" (Box 29, Folder 748)
  - London (Box 29, Folder 749)
  - Loose notes (Box 29, Folder 750)
  - "The Man Who Discovered The Panda" (Box 29, Folder 751)
  - "Monster In The Lake" (Box 29, Folder 752)
  - Manatee research (Box 29, Folder 753-755)
  - Miscellaneous book ideas (Box 29, Folder 756)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 29, Folder 757-758)
  - Miscellaneous from desk top (Box 29, Folder 759-761)
  - Miscellaneous ideas (Box 29, Folder 762-764)
  - Miscellaneous notes, circa 1950s (Box 29, Folder 765)
  - Miscellaneous notes (mostly animals) (Box 29, Folder 766-767)
  - Miscellaneous papers and photograph (Box 29, Folder 768)
  - Miscellaneous proposals (Box 29, Folder 769)
  - "My Life As A Vampire Bat" (Box 29, Folder 770)
  - National Geographic magazine, 1976 March (Box 29, Folder 771)
  - Natural history magazine clippings (Box 29, Folder 772-773)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 29, Folder 774)
  - New York Times Book Review, 2003 November 16 (Box 29, Folder 775)
  - Notebooks (Box 29, Folder 776-777)
  - Notebooks (Box 30, Folder 778-782)
  - "Not Using" (Box 30, Folder 783)
  - Okapi and Porcupine research (Box 30, Folder 784)
  - Old proposals (Box 30, Folder 785)
  - Panda ideas (Box 30, Folder 786)
  - Panda notes (Box 30, Folder 787-789)
  - Panda research (Box 30, Folder 790)
  - "Penguin Hall of Fame" (Box 30, Folder 791)
  - Penguin, early proposals (Box 30, Folder 792)
  - Penguin notes (Box 30, Folder 793-797)
  - People - human interest clippings (Box 30, Folder 798)
  - Pigeon notes (Box 30, Folder 799)
  - Poems, animals, sources (Box 30, Folder 800)
  - Polar Bear notes (Box 30, Folder 801)
  - Prehistoric clippings (Box 30, Folder 802-804)
  - Proposal on baby animals (Box 30, Folder 805)
  - "The Puzzle Of The Dinosaur Bird" (Box 30, Folder 806)
  - "The Puzzle Of The Dinosaur Bird" (Box 31, Folder 807)
  - "Pygmy - Forest People" (Box 31, Folder 808)
  - Rescued animals (Box 31, Folder 809)
  - "Reproduction fees - still to pay" (Box 31, Folder 810)
  - Safari research (Box 31, Folder 811)
  - "Samples HBV" (Box 31, Folder 812-813)
  - San Diego Animal Photos (Box 31, Folder 814)
  - "Scribner - My Work" (Box 31, Folder 815)
  - Sea Animal clips (Box 31, Folder 816)
  - Sea Horse research (Box 31, Folder 817)
  - "Sea Legends" (Box 31, Folder 818)
  - Seal research (Box 31, Folder 819)
  - "Sleep Safe" (Box 31, Folder 820)
  - Squirrel research (Box 31, Folder 821-822)
  - "Summer '99" ideas, circa 1999 (Box 31, Folder 823)
  - Talks (Box 31, Folder 824)
  - "Textbook Photocopies and notes (on Dinosaurs)" (Box 31, Folder 825)
  - Textbook writing samples (Box 31, Folder 826)
  - "That's Not The Worst Of It", notes (Box 31, Folder 827)
  - "Then And Now: Giants Of The Past" (Box 31, Folder 828)
  - Thomas Jefferson clippings (Box 31, Folder 829)
  - Vacations (Box 31, Folder 830)
  - Various clippings (Box 31, Folder 831)
  - Whale research (Box 31, Folder 832)
  - "Whale and Bat", notes and clippings (Box 31, Folder 833)
  - "What The Elephant Was" (Box 31, Folder 834-839)
    Includes notes, research, proofs and a copy of the "What The Elephant Was" book cover.
  - "Why Does My Cat Do That?", notes and clippings (Box 31, Folder 840)
  - Wildlife articles (Box 31, Folder 841)
  - Wildlife clippings (Box 31, Folder 842)
  - Wildlife Environment Clips (Box 32, Folder 843-844)
  - Wild World of Animals (Box 32, Folder 845)
  - Women / Accomplishment (Box 32, Folder 846)
  - Writing Samples (Box 32, Folder 847)
  - Year of the Panda Background (Box 32, Folder 848)
  - "Young Panda Proposal" (Box 32, Folder 849)
  - Zion National Monument & Endangered Animal's List (Box 32, Folder 850)
- Correspondence, 1954-2002; Series III; 2.25
  This series consists of correspondence with publishers, authors, fans, and others, relating to the publication and reception of Schlein's books. Correspondence can also be found in Writing Files and Research Material.
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order by subject or correspondenct.
  - "Animal Photo Sources" (Box 32, Folder 851)
  - "Regarding August Screenplay" (Box 32, Folder 852)
  - August Submits (Box 32, Folder 853)
  - Author's Guild & League Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 854)
  - "Awards, etc." (Box 32, Folder 855)
  - "H. Barton / Brenner Ill. Course", circa 1986-1995 (Box 32, Folder 856)
  - "Behrman Usage", circa 1984 (Box 32, Folder 857)
  - Book Donations (Box 32, Folder 858)
  - Boono Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 859)
  - "Bradbury Correspondence" (Box 32, Folder 860)
  - Cartoon Ideas (Box 32, Folder 861)
  - Coral Reef Correspondence & Proposals (Box 32, Folder 862)
  - "Correspondence" (Box 32, Folder 863)
    Includes letters from Maurice Sendak.
  - Correspondence and Clippings (Box 32, Folder 864)
  - "Cyrilly Abels, Agent" (Box 32, Folder 865)
  - Dinosaur (Box 32, Folder 866)
  - Editor Letters (Box 32, Folder 867)
  - Family History (Box 32, Folder 868)
  - Fan Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 869)
  - "Fan Mail 1960's, 1970's", circa 1960s-1970s (Box 32, Folder 870)
  - "Fan Mail" (Box 32, Folder 871-873)
  - "Fan Mail" - Boone Elementary School Chicago, circa 2002 (Box 32, Folder 874)
  - "Fan Mail", various student correspondence, circa 1990 (Box 32, Folder 875-876)
  - Gablers (Box 32, Folder 877)
  - "Gale - Something About the Author" (Box 32, Folder 878-879)
  - "Go with the Sun re-issue with Walker" (Box 32, Folder 880)
  - Harper (Box 32, Folder 881)
  - "Henry's Ride", circa 1954-1955 (Box 33, Folder 882)
    Includes correspondence regarding "City Boy Country Boy".
  - Hastings House (Box 33, Folder 883)
  - Here Comes the Night & Family's (Box 33, Folder 884)
  - "Home Exchange" (Box 33, Folder 885)
  - "Jellybean" (Box 33, Folder 886)
  - "JLG & Trumeet & Kerlan" (Box 33, Folder 887)
  - "Juju" (Box 33, Folder 888)
  - Letters (Box 33, Folder 889)
  - "Letters of Recommendation" (Box 33, Folder 890)
  - Letters to the Times (Box 33, Folder 891)
  - Loose Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 892)
  - Loose Material (Box 33, Folder 893)
  - "Master Publist & SS Letter" (Box 33, Folder 894)
  - McClintock, Lillian (Box 33, Folder 895)
  - McGregor, Herman manuscript (Box 33, Folder 896)
  - Memories (Box 33, Folder 897)
  - Metric (Box 33, Folder 898)
  - Miscellaneous Letters (Box 33, Folder 899)
  - Miscellaneous Publication Letters (Box 33, Folder 900)
  - "My Correspondence" (Box 33, Folder 901)
  - "Note & First Draft - Metric" (Box 33, Folder 902)
  - "Oomi" (Box 33, Folder 903)
  - Panda Watch Legal (Box 33, Folder 904)
  - "PEN Brouhaha" (Box 33, Folder 905)
  - "Penguin" (Box 33, Folder 906)
  - Personal (Box 33, Folder 907)
  - "Photo", circa 1980 (Box 33, Folder 908)
  - Publishing Rights Letters (Box 33, Folder 909)
  - "Puppy's House" (Box 33, Folder 910)
  - "The Puzzle of the Dinosaur-Bird" (Box 33, Folder 911)
  - "Rabbit's World" (Box 33, Folder 912)
  - "The Raggle, Taggle Fellow" (Box 33, Folder 913)
  - "Rejection Letters" (Box 33, Folder 914)
  - "Response to Come" (Box 34, Folder 915)
  - Reversion of Rights Letters (Box 34, Folder 916)
  - Silver Bwidet (Box 34, Folder 917)
  - Simon & Schuster (Box 34, Folder 918-919)
  - Silver Building, circa 1983 (Box 34, Folder 920)
  - "Snow" (Box 34, Folder 921)
  - "Squirrel #3" (Box 34, Folder 922)
  - Submission & Rejection Letters (Box 34, Folder 923)
  - Treimel, Scott (Box 34, Folder 924)
  - Vacation Exchange Program Letter (Box 34, Folder 925)
  - Various Rejections (Box 34, Folder 926-928)
  - Various Correspondence, circa 1956 (Box 34, Folder 929-930)
  - Vietnam Petition (Box 34, Folder 931)
  - Willliams, Vera (Box 34, Folder 932)
- Personal Papers, 1976-2004; Series IV; 4
  This series includes photographs, financial papers, awards, book lists, printed material, and audio-visual material, variously relating to aspects of Schlein's personal and professional life.
  Files are largely arranged in alphabetical order with printed material and audio-visual material arranged at the end.
  - Apartment Plans (Box 34, Folder 933)
  - "Attic Inventory" (Box 34, Folder 934)
  - Author's Guild (Box 34, Folder 935)
  - Author's Guild Bulletin (Box 34, Folder 936)
  - Author's Guild Mailings / Forum of Writers (Box 34, Folder 937)
  - "Awards" (Box 34, Folder 938)
  - Bank Account Books (Box 34, Folder 939-940)
  - Big Talk Legal (Box 34, Folder 941)
  - Birthday Card (Box 34, Folder 942)
  - Books & Sales (Box 34, Folder 943)
  - Brooklyn College Reunion Information - 50th, circa 2002 (Box 34, Folder 944)
  - Butzel Test (Box 34, Folder 945)
  - Calendar, circa 2002-2003 (Box 34, Folder 946)
  - Cardozo Law School Applications (Box 34, Folder 947)
  - Children's Book Com PEN (Box 34, Folder 948)
  - "Children's Book Council", member list (Box 34, Folder 949)
  - Children's Book People (Box 34, Folder 950)
  - "Children's Books of the Year", circa 1990 (Box 34, Folder 951)
  - College Essays and Articles (Box 34, Folder 952)
  - Concept Books Redo Proposal (Box 34, Folder 953)
  - Co op Finance Notes (Box 35, Folder 954)
  - "Critical Comment on Work of Miriam Schlein" (Box 35, Folder 955-958)
  - Dragon Notes (Box 35, Folder 959)
  - "Good Stationary Clippings" (Box 35, Folder 960)
  - "Honor Awarded" (Box 35, Folder 961)
  - Income Charts (Box 35, Folder 962)
  - "Internet List My Books" (Box 35, Folder 963)
  - Job Resume and Assorted Stories (Box 35, Folder 964)
  - Lawsuit, 1999 (Box 35, Folder 965)
  - "Lecture Union and Panda" (Box 35, Folder 966)
  - "List of Books" (Box 35, Folder 967)
  - "Little Seal" and Other Stories; National Geographic-Coral Reef, circa 1993 (Box 35, Folder 968)
    Also includes "Mouse", "The Whole Big World", and "The Wonder of Things".
  - Loose Papers (Box 35, Folder 969-971)
  - Loose Papers from Under Computer (Box 35, Folder 972-974)
  - Miscellaneous Desk Work (Box 35, Folder 975)
  - Miscellaneous Financial from Desk (Box 35, Folder 976)
  - Miscellaneous from Office (Box 35, Folder 977-978)
  - "Misc., My Family" (Box 35, Folder 979)
  - "More Than One" Handout (Box 35, Folder 980)
  - New York Academy of Science Honors (Box 35, Folder 981)
  - Newspaper Press Release, Circa 1976 (Box 35, Folder 982)
  - Notebooks and Passport (Box 35, Folder 983)
  - Notes of Good Luck (Box 35, Folder 984)
  - Obituaries (Box 35, Folder 985)
  - "Old Pub. List" 1980, circa 1980 (Box 35, Folder 986)
  - "Old Pub. List" 1996, Circa 1996 (Box 35, Folder 987)
  - "Old Resumes" (Box 35, Folder 988)
  - Pay Records, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 989)
  - "Photographs" (Box 35, Folder 990)
  - "Pile of Junk Redo" (Box 35, Folder 991)
  - "Printed Bio Who's Who" (Box 35, Folder 992)
  - "Printed Critiques on Books" (Box 35, Folder 993)
  - "Promo" (Box 35, Folder 994)
  - Resume-2002 Pub. List, circa 2002 (Box 35, Folder 995)
  - "Publicity for B.C." (Box 35, Folder 996)
  - "Publicity Cuttings" (Box 35, Folder 997)
  - "Quotable Reviews" (Box 36, Folder 998)
  - The Race of the Golden Apples posters (Box 36, Folder 999)
  - Royalties Info (Box 36, Folder 1000)
  - Social Security (Box 36, Folder 1001-1002)
  - "'Special Sales' Ripoff" (Box 36, Folder 1003)
  - Submetering Co-op Finance Notes (Box 36, Folder 1004)
  - "Tax Information" (Box 36, Folder 1005)
  - Taxes, circa 1984-2000 (Box 36, Folder 1006-1007)
  - "Times Letter--Re: Animals" (Box 36, Folder 1008)
  - Various Notes and Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 1009)
  - Various Reviews (Box 36, Folder 1010-1017)
  - Various Reviews (Box 37, Folder 1018)
  - Weekly Calendars, circa 1985-1999 (Box 37, Folder 1019)
  - Weekly Calendars, circa 2000-2001 (Box 37, Folder 1020)
  - "What is Where" (Box 37, Folder 1021)
  - Printed Material
    See also Magazines and Guidance Associates Sound Filmstrips - Measurement: From Cubits to Centimeters
    - Albert Whitman & Company: Spring Catalog, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 1022)
    - Art Catalogs (Box 37, Folder 1023-1025)
    - The Art Wolfe Collection Catalogs (Box 37, Folder 1026)
    - Children's Book Catalog, circa 1980-2004 (Box 37, Folder 1027)
    - Catalogs (Box 37, Folder 1028-1029)
    - Science Books, Pamphlet, and Note (Box 37, Folder 1030)
    - Various (Box 37, Folder 1031-1033)
    - Various Pamphlets (Box 37, Folder 1034)
    - "Various Materials" (Box 37, Folder 1035)
    - Various Office Material (Box 37, Folder 1036)
  - Audio-Visual Material
    - Photographic slides (Box 38, Folder 1037)
    - Phonographic record (Box 41 (Record album storage), Folder 1042)
    - Phonographic record (Box 42 (Record album storage), Folder 1043)
    - Phonographic record (Box 43 (Record album storage), Folder 1044)
- Oversize, 0.5
  - Magazines, 1952-1971 (Box 39, Folder 1038-1040)
  - Guidance Associates Sound Filmstrips - Measurement: From Cubits to Centimeters, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 1041)